## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & MECHANICAL ENGINEER

# **GLENN WINBO SONDELL**

# **ABOUT ME**

I'm a mechanical engineer and a software developer. My multidisciplinary background helps me understand the needs and challenges that people of different backgrounds face. This makes me an excellent developer, problem solver, communicator and team-player.

I can help you with anything from writing firmware in Rust to machine learning in Python. I have great math skills and use them to solve problems related to 3D graphics, modeling and physics simulations.

## **Background:**

I started out as a mechanical engineer, but I have changed tracks towards software development. The reason behind this change was simple, I love to create things and learn about new technologies. In particular I was drawn to software development because it allows for faster iterations. Just compile and you get new a prototype. Even rust compiles faster than a 3D-printer!

While I have more experience using python, I prefer to use Rust whenever possible. Having used mypy in larger projects, I prefer to have strong typing built into the language itself.

# EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Alten Sverige AB 2018-06-01 .. ongoing

At Alten I have worked with wide range different projects. Within product development I have worked with mechanicaldesign, electronics and software development. See the project sections for details.

Role & Responsibilities

Product development, consulting.

consulting

#### Materials Research 2015-08-01 .. 2016-09-01

At Jönköping University I supported research activities as a lab-technician.

Role & Responsibilities

CNC-machining, test-rigs, assisting with experiments.

SolidWorks | MasterCam | LabView

# SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Professional experience of software development.

#### Desktop CAD App 2022-08-01 .. ongoing

Created an application for **Cerlnvent** that allows the user to generate molds for manufacturing dental crowns.

Python NumPy SciPy PyQt PyMadCad Gmsh PyVista CATIA GitHub CI/CD

## Al Student Workshop 2022-06-01 .. ongoing

Helped Alten attract students by preparing a workshop for Machine-Learning master students. 

Repository

Role & Responsibilities

Preparation of source code and data for the event. Deployment example using Flask.

Python NumPy Pandas TensorFlow Keras Flask RNN GitHub Docker DigitalOcean

## Medical Device 2021-09-01 .. 2022-02-01

Developed Multi4, a device for taking biopsy samples for cancer-diagnostics.

Role & Responsibilities

Firmware for embedded device, mechanical design, prototyping and testing.

Arduino SolidWorks

#### Hygiene Device 2021-05-01 .. 2021-10-01

Developed the **Paprtect** prototype, a finger cover dispenser for public touchscreens.

Role & Responsibilities

Firmware for embedded device, pcb design, prototyping and testing.

Arduino X KiCad

## MedTech Startup 2020-12-01 .. 2022-12-01

Started the company **Orthovelox AB**, that aims to produce innovative solutions for orthopedic healthcare. Orthovelox developes design software based on 3D scanning.

Role & Responsibilities

Product Development, Software development, Project-Lead, Fund raising.

Python NumPy SciPy PyVista GitHub CI/CD Azure PyTest mypy 3D-Modeling

# **IoT Device** 2020-12-01 .. 2022-12-01

Developed proof of concept for Progressive Safety.

Role & Responsibilities

Firmware for development boards, testing and PCB cost estimates.

Arduino c++ BlueTooth

#### Electric Forklift 2019-03-01 .. 2019-08-01

Helped **Helge Nyberg** develop an electric forklift for indoor use. The forklift uses force sensors instead of a conventional user interface.

Role & Responsibilities

Firmware for processing user input to actions and emulation of inertia.

Arduino

# PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Professional experience of product development (without software development).

## Mechatronic Components 2022-04-01 .. 2021-01-01

Helped Husqvarna with product maintenance and development of motor controllers, HMI panels and motors used in handheld battery powered products.

Role & Responsibilities

Coordinated product development between different Husqvarna sites and subcontractors. Mechanical design and configuration management of mechatronic components.



#### Disposable Medical Device 2020-03-01 .. 2020-06-01

Designed a disposable flashlight for gynecology examinations.

Role & Responsibilities

Mechanical design and testing.

SolidWorks

#### **Automotive Accessories** 2018-04-01 .. 2020-04-01

At Thule I developed torque keys, load carries and roof boxes. I also developed a friction drilling production method and helped with migration from version control systems.

Role & Responsibilities

Mechanical design, testing, prototyping and production development.

SolidWorks | SmarTeam | YaPdm

# SIDE PROJECTS AND AUTODIDACTISM

Various for fun projects that have improved my skills.

#### **Product Configurator** 2023-11-14 .. 2023-12-01

A proof of concept where a chair rendered as a 3D model and based on meta-data about the 3D model a number UI elements are dynamically generated. So that same binary application could be used show how many different products can be configured. Only the frontend was made. Pepo



#### delamat.se 2023-09-04 .. ongoing

A sideproject where the plan is to make a website where users can share recipes and shopinglists. The main purpose of this sideproject is learning how to use htmx and axum in practice. Prepo. Webbsite: Not yet deployed.



### halfedge lib 2023-05-24 .. ongoing

I have been frustrated with available libraries for rust and python for boolean operations on 3D-models. Therefore I started this project that aims to provide an opensoruce rust library with python bindings. The ambition is to provide robust boolean operations on halfedge datastructres. The project is heavly inspired by the white paper: Exact, robust, and efficient regularized Booleans on general 3D meshes. Repo.



# Web Resume 2023-02-01 .. ongoing

I maintain my resume as a website and the source code is available at AitHub.



## WASM Web App 2023-01-01 .. 2023-01-10

Implemented Conway's Game of Life as a Webb app using rust. Repo



## Python Cad Library 2022-12-01 .. ongoing

I contribute to the capabilities of MADCAD, an opensource python CAD library.



#### Daily Driver: NixOS 2022-11-01 .. ongoing

I use Linux for both work and personal projects. Currently I use NixOS and benefits from the robust development environments it offers.



# Embedded Rust 2022-07-01 .. 2022-10-01

I made simple data acquisition firmware using rust for stm32 and nrf52 development boards. As a compliment I also made a desktop app to plot values from the devices.



# The Rust Book 2022-05-01 .. 2022-07-01

Taught myself rust using the Book and fell in love.

Rust

# FORMAL EDUCATION

Just a starting point...

Master: Mechanics 2016-08-01 .. 2018-06-01

At Jönköping University I studied product development, materials engineering and design optimization.

SolidWorks CATIA FEA MatLab Visual Basic

Project: Solar Car 2014-08-01 .. 2015-12-01

Designed and built a solar powered car. Competed with the car in the World Solar Challenge, a 3000km long race on the public roads of Australia.

Role & Responsibilities

System Engineering, Battery and Solar Panel design, CNC-machining.

SolidWorks FEA MasterCam Arduino

Bachelor: Mechanics 2012-08-01 .. 2017-06-01

At Jönköping University I studied product development, materials engineering and design automation.

SolidWorks FEA MatLab Visual Basic PLC



LETS TALK

○ GlennWSo

Mail me

Web CV

**SKILLS** Arduino BlueTooth 3D-Modeling axum Azure CATIA CI/CD consulting CSS cross-platform DigitalOcean Docker egui FEA Flask GitHub Gmsh HTML HTMX Keras KiCad LabView Linux MatLab MasterCam mypy Nix nrf52 **PLC PyMadCad** NumPy open-source **Pandas** PyVista RNN SciPy **PyQt PyTest Python** Rust stm32 SmarTeam SolidWorks sqlx SSG Teams USB **WASM TensorFlow** Tera three-d Visual Basic YaPdm windows Zola web